Now, to install external packages, you use PIP, but make sure that you know your packages.
There's a lot of packages in the Python package index.
You can browse them at pipi.org.
So for example, let's look up a request and we should see the library that we're looking
for right here.
Make sure that you check and see, well, okay, this has 43,000 stars on GitHub.
It's probably the right thing.
There are a lot of libraries that have similar names, and there have been malicious
libraries that have popped up for common misspellings.
So it's very important to verify your external package names
before you run the command.
Better yet, copy the package name, straight from pipi.
If we go here, there's just a big blue button here where you can copy it.
So you don't have to risk typing it in and getting it wrong.
A little bit about the request library.
We saw it early on in the course.
It allows us to make requests and get back responses.
The first thing we would want to do is import it.
And let's use the Shibae Online API, which returns a Shibae dog.
Is that the right way of pronouncing it?
Shibae?
I'm going to go, I'm going to go with that.
But TLDR API with cube puppies.
So now that you've installed requests in your virtual environment,
you can copy this file.
And we're going to call it chibae.py.
And we're going to run it.
And what we did here was define a URL.
We got a response by calling request.get.
We found out what the status code was in this case.
It was 200.
We got the results as JSON.
And then we printed it out.
So we got a list with an image URL.
I'm going to click on it.
It is adorable.
Yeah, I'll puppy.
Cool.
So how do we deal with errors?
If we try to pass in a non-existent URL,
we're going to get a 404.
So we want to make sure that we check the status code.
And we can also pass in different parameters.
When we use the request library, just like this.
And let's copy this whole thing over.
Oops, that is not what I wanted.
No, I have, I have angered my repel.
Let's reopen that again.
So here, I am now defining a parameters count 10.
And I'm passing in those parameters with the request.
I'm getting that JSON.
And now because it's a list that has multiple items in it,
I am looping over it and printing it out.
Now I have 10 puppy pictures to choose from.
I'm going to open this one very cute.
So that's how you pass in parameters.
That's the thousand-level overview of the request library.
If you want to learn more about it after the class, take a look at the quick start.
It's very powerful.
So we are now going to take a short break.
Let's say about 20 minutes.
And over break, take a look at the practice for object-oriented Python.
Go ahead and skip over the practice for inheritance and come back to it after class.
It's a more involved topic and follow through with the practice for libraries and modules.
Once we come back from break, we're going to talk about our final topic,
which is web frameworks and Django.
I'm sure your brains are totally full of knowledge right now.
Before we go on break, are there any questions?
Can you have multiple tries?
Generally not.
Now I think that's a syntax error in Python.
And for questions like that,
I would recommend that you type them out in the ruffle.
That would be a very quick and easy way to get an answer for that.
Yeah, there we go.
So as soon as I try that, I get a syntax error.
Each try needs to have an accepted associated with it,
one or more, and then you can have separate try blocks later on in your code.